baseball-reference.com 2007-12-14

# Privacy Statement - SPORTS REFERENCE, Inc. - Baseball-Reference.com

## Baseball-Reference.com-- Baseball's History: 1871-Now

A combination of sites providing top-notch statistics and resources for sports fans everywhere. 

This Privacy Statement sets forth the information-gathering, use, and dissemination practices of Sports Reference, Inc., its subsidiaries, and affiliates (collectively referred to as "SRI") in connection with the World Wide Web sites located at www.sports-reference.com, www.baseball-reference.com, www.pro-football-reference.com, www.basketball-reference.com, www.baseballbooks.net, and all other Web sites owned or operated by SRI (the "Site"). This Privacy Statement addresses SRI's practices regarding information collected only directly through or from the Site \- it does not address or govern any information gathering, use, or dissemination practices related to information collected other than directly through or from the Site, including, without limitation, from or via telephone, facsimile, postal mail, personal delivery, or other or additional offline means or media. SRI can be contacted by mail, phone, facsimile, or by e-mail at SRI, as provided in Paragraph 3 of this Privacy Statement. 

## 1\. Collection of Personal Information from Site Visitors

SRI may collect or track (1) the home server domain names, e-mail addresses, type of client computer, files downloaded, search engine used, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to the Site, (2) the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with SRI via e-mail, (3) information knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms, surveys, e-mail, contest entries, and other online avenues (including, without limitation, demographic and personal profile data), and (4) aggregate and user-specific information regarding which pages Site visitors access. 

SRI may place Internet "cookies" on visitors' hard drives. Internet cookies save data about individual visitors, such as the visitor's name, password, user-name, shopping cart, screen preferences, and the pages of the Site viewed by the visitor. When the visitor revisits the Site, SRI may recognize the visitor by the Internet cookie and customize the visitor's experience accordingly, for example, in pre-filling forms. Visitors may decline or remove Internet cookies, if any, by using the appropriate feature of their Web client software, if available. 

SRI also may use Web bugs to gather, store, and track certain information related to your visit to and activity on the Site. A Web bug is a file object, which can be a graphic image such as a transparent one pixel-by-one pixel graphics file, which is placed on a Web page or in an e-mail message to monitor user activity. A Web bug can gather, for example, the IP address of your computer, the time the Web page was viewed, and the type of browser used. 

When a visitor performs a search within the Site, SRI may record information identifying the visitor or linking the visitor to the search performed. SRI may also record limited information for every search request and use that information to solve technical problems with the services available directly or indirectly in connection with the Site, and to calculate overall usage statistics. 

##  2\. Payment Information

We use third-party payment service providers such as Amazon.com� and PayPal� to handle any monetary transactions. SRI does not store any of your private payment information provided by you directly to these service providers. 

## 3\. Comments, Notices and Chat Rooms

Comments posted to any of our Web pages are public. All other notices sent to SRI should use the following address or contact information: 

         Sports Reference, Inc.
         6757 Greene St, Suite 315
         Philadelphia, PA  19119
         Fax 800/660-5292
         Phone 215/301-9181
         sf@sports-reference.com

With respect to chat rooms, SRI does not, and is not obligated to, monitor or review any areas on the Site, or the content therein, where users transmit or post communications or communicate with each other regarding SRI or Content (see Terms and Conditions) on the Site, including but not limited to, communications in chat rooms, bulletin boards or other user forums. As such, SRI assumes no liability for the accuracy of such information, no duty to update or correct such information, and no liability for such communications arising under the laws of copyright, libel, privacy, obscenity, or otherwise. 

## 4\. Use of Personal Data Collected

Personal data collected by SRI may be used by SRI for many reasons, for example, for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, for a statistical analysis of users' behavior, for product development, for content improvement, for fulfillment of a requested transaction or record-keeping, or to customize the content and layout of the Site. Aggregate data on visitors' home servers may be used for internal purposes, and individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information which visitors voluntarily provide to SRI may be added to SRI's databases and used for future calls and mailings regarding Site updates, new products and services, and upcoming events. 

With respect to visitor e-mail addresses, we allow users to post their e-mail address on comments or in sponsorships, in the event that they wish to allow others to reach them easily. Visitor e-mail addresses from comments are not used by SRI to generate mailing lists. 

SRI also may use Site visitor data to contact the Site visitors regarding account status and changes to the Terms and Conditions, any subscriber agreement, this Privacy Statement, and any other policies or agreements relevant to Site visitors. 

## 5\. Disclosure of Personal Data to Third Parties

Subject to the limitations of Paragraph 4, aggregate data on visitors' home servers may be provided to third parties such as marketing firms. 

Identifiable and non-identifiable visitor information and data which visitors provide to SRI may be provided to third parties who provide products, information, or services which SRI believes that visitors may be interested in directly or indirectly purchasing or obtaining. Identifiable or non-identifiable data also may be disclosed or distributed to another party with which SRI enters or reasonably may enter into a corporate transaction, such as, for example, a merger, consolidation, acquisition, or asset purchase, or to a third party pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, in response to a request by or on behalf of any local, state, federal, or other government agency, department, or body, whether or not pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, or if determined by SRI in its sole judgment that such disclosure or distribution is appropriate to protect the life, health, security, or property of SRI or any other person or entity. 

While SRI will undertake efforts to see that any third party to which SRI shares, rents, sells, or otherwise discloses personal data is under a contractual obligation to use the personal data solely for the purposes for which the data was disclosed, such third parties are independent third parties over which SRI exercises no control, and SRI is not responsible for their conduct, actions, omissions, or information handling or dissemination practices and SRI will not be liable therefor. 

This Site may contain links to other World Wide Web sites or advertisements for or placed by third parties. SRI is not responsible for the privacy practices of such Web sites, advertisers, or third parties, or for the content of such sites or advertisements. It is possible that these links or advertisements, themselves, may be used by third parties or others to collect personal or other information about Site visitors. It is solely the visitor's obligation to review and understand the privacy practices and policies of these other Web sites and of these advertisers and third parties. 

## 6\. Security Measures

SRI has implemented numerous security features to prevent the unauthorized release of or access to personal information. For example, SRI: undertakes all efforts to maintain a secure server; does not store any user credit card information; and requires employees and service providers who work for or with SRI to sign confidentiality and security contracts restricting their use of any data related to user information. Please be advised, however, that the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from SRI via this Site or e-mail cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, SRI is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. Instead of communicating with SRI via e-mail or the Internet, visitors can contact SRI by mail, phone, or facsimile, as provided in Paragraph 3 of this Privacy Statement. 

## 7\. Opt-Out Right

Except as necessary for SRI to provide the services, information, or products requested by a visitor, the visitor may opt out of having his or her personally identifiable information, which has been voluntarily provided to SRI through an account registration, customer order, or electronic news or information subscription, prospectively retained by SRI, used by SRI for secondary purposes, or disclosed by SRI to third parties by contacting SRI via postal mail, e-mail, or facsimile at the addresses set out above. (This does not apply to collection of the type of Web browser of the visitor to the Site or to information provided or collected that does not meet the above description.) By way of illustration, you have the option to remove your name from any of our mailing lists at any time. 

## 8\. Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

Upon a visitor's request via postal mail, e-mail, or facsimile, SRI will provide to the visitor a summary of any personally identifiable information retained by SRI regarding the visitor, which information has been voluntarily provided to SRI through an account registration, customer order, or electronic news or information subscription. A visitor may modify, correct, change or update their personally identifiable information by contacting SRI via postal mail, e-mail, facsimile, or telephone as provided in Paragraph 3 of this Privacy Statement. 

## 9\. Right to Change Privacy Statement

SRI may change this Privacy Statement at any time. Notice of any new or revised Privacy Statement, as well as the location of the new or revised statement, will be posted on the Site for at least 60 days after the change. It is the obligation of users visiting the Site to learn of changes to the Privacy Statement since their last visit. Any change to this Privacy Statement shall be effective as to all visitors once instituted, including as to any visitor who previously visited the Site before the change was made. 

## Effective Date: October 1, 2004

## Last Updated: October 28, 2004

Stats updated through October 28, 2007.

Copyright © 2000-2007 Sports Reference, Inc. All rights reserved.    
[A Sports Reference, Inc. Site](http://www.sports-reference.com/) : About BR | Privacy Statement | Conditions & Terms of Service
